Guide to the C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers, 1930-1988 MS2028
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers
1930-1988
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Stolzenbach, C. Darwin
MS2028
41 Linear Feet
The C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers consists of correspondence and memoranda, bound and unbound reports, original and photocopied news clippings, documents related to civil action suits pertaining to highway legislation, excerpts from law review magazines, press releases, copies of speeches, minutes and agendas of meetings, original and photocopied Congressional and other legislation, photographs, and maps.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the collection was donated to the Gelman Library in 1989, with another major accretion coming in 1991. Future accretions to the collection are not anticipated.
Historical or Biographical Note
The C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers relate to the history of WMATA and of regional mass transportation. The material dates from 1930 through 1988, with only one item, a report in Washington traffic problems, dating from 1930. The bulk of the documents date from 1960 to 1969. Documents dating from 1979 through 1988 are related primarily to Stolzenbach's three-year tenure as Chairman and President of the Institute for the Study of Transportation
The Papers were the private collection of C. Darwin Stolzenbach, accumulated over the course of twenty-five years. Information as to how he acquired many of those documents (such as related to the reading files and the civil action suits) is absent from either the donor file or Stolzenbach's personal correspondence. All rights, such as they were held by the donor at the time of transfer, were transferred to the George Washington University at the time of donation. Further, no restrictions on the use of the documents in the collection were made by the donor at the times of tranfer.
The C. Darwin Stolzenbach Papers, together with four other manuscript collections, were processed under a grant from the National Historic Publications and Records Commission. The grant, entitled "The Nation's Hometown History" was awarded in the fall of 1990. This collection complements other Department of Special Collections holdings related to the history of WMATA and of regional mass transportation. Relevant manuscript collections for further research include the: Cody Pfanstiehl Papers, WMATA Metro History Project Collection, WMATA Metrorail Specifications Collection, and Greater Washington Board of Trade Records.
C. Darwin Stolzenbach, who changed his last name to Fairweather sometime during the early 1980's, studied physics at MIT from 1932 to 1935. Soon thereafter, he moved to the Washington area, attending the George Washington University from 1939 to 1935, where he studied political science, and the American University from 1941 to 1942, studying public administration.
From 1941 to 1944 he served in the Office of the Chief of Engineers in the United States Army Air Forces as a program analyst. Following that, for four years beginning in 1944, Stolzenbach worked as an economist in the Bureau of the Budget, and beginning in 1948 as Special Assistant to the Secretary of Commerce for Transportation Policy Planning. In 1951 he became a senior operations research analyst at the Johns Hopkins University's Operations Research Office. There he conducted assessments of the defense of the United States from attack by missiles and bombers.
In 1961, Stolzenbach was named by President Kennedy to replace H. Holmes Vogel as Administrator of the National Capital Transportation Agency (NCTA), who had himself been appointed by President Eisenhower. Until his resignation in 1965, Stolzenbach oversaw the development and application of a comprehensive highway and mass transit plan for the National Capital region. By 1965, the NCTA had laid the foundations for a subway system and drafted plans for the proposed Inner Loop, I-266, and Three Sisters Bridge projects. In his letter of resignation, Stolzenbach made it clear that the research and operations analysis having been completed, Stolzenbach believed that he had guided the NCTA through those phases that required his expertise. He was succeeded by Walter McCarter.
As an advisory agency, the NCTA did not actually implement the plans that it proposed. That job fell to the Department of Transportation. However, the Agency did conduct extensive research and studies to determine the feasibility of subways and inner-city expressways. Most of the highway proposals submitted by the NCTA were eventually abandoned; controversy and lawsuits slowed their development for over ten years. The subway system was not adopted in the form proposed by the NCTA, but served as the basis for the system proposed by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA). WMATA succeeded the NCTA as the agency charged with implementing the Capital-region mass transit proj ect. Established in 1967 by a Charter between the governments of the District of Columbia, Maryland, and Virginia, the WMATA was granted the authority to construct, not merely advise. In this capacity, WMATA completed at least part of the work first mapped out by the NCTA.
First in 1979 and again in 1984, Stolzenbach established research projects. The first, the Metro History Project, was funded by a grant from the Mass Transportation Administration. The second, the Institute for the Study of Transportation, was a taxexempt research organization. Both projects were dedicated to writing monographs and manuscripts on the history of the highway and subway projects in the Washington area. Apparently, much of the material in Stolzenbach's collection was reorganized as he consulted it during his research.
Collection Scope and Content
The C. Darwin Stolzenbach papers consists of correspondence and memoranda, bound and unbound reports, original and photocopied news clippings, documents related to civil action suits pertaining to highway legislation, excerpts from law review magazines, press releases, copies of speeches, minutes and agendas of meetings, original and photocopied Congressional and other legislation, photographs, and maps.
As a source of information about the history of the local highway and mass transit systems, this collection is invaluable. Though it is in parts incomplete and eclectic, it has a very broad range of material relating to nearly all facets of the development of highways in the Washington metropolitan area from the late 1950's to the early 1970's, and many valuable documents on the establishment of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact between the State of Maryland, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Virginia from 1963 to 1967. The collection includes an exhaustive set of local-area newspaper clippings.
While pre-dating the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA), the successor to the NCTA, the collection has copies of agreements, resolutions, and legislation that established the Authority. The NCTA was deeply involved in the development of the proposed Interstate 266 and the Three Sisters Bridge, and the collection has an exhaustive collection of maps, correspondence, news clippings, and civil action suits relating to these projects. And, because many documents were filed as evidence in these civil suits, the collection is rich in related documents that would not have otherwise crossed Stolzenbach's desk.
As Administrator of the NCTA, Stolzenbach acquired copies of important legislation and studies of parking and highways dating from the 1930's and 1940's. In collecting related material for the preparation of his history monographs and manuscripts, Stolzenbach also accumulated many reports and manuscripts on the history of highways and the Metro. Because of this, the collection as a whole presents an unusually comprehensive general history of highway and transportation legislation in the Washington area.
The dates of the documents in this collection range from 1876 (reproduced in a later publication) to 1988. The bulk of the documents date from 1961 to 1966. Most of the correspondence dates from 1961 through 1965, when Darwin Stolzenbach served as Administrator of the National Capital Transportation Agency (NCTA). During and subsequent to his term at the Agency, Stolzenbach collected a broad range of information related to the development of highways and public transportation, with an emphasis on those developments in the Washington metropolitan area, as well as documents related to the projects of the NCTA.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series: Administrator, NCTA; President METRO 2001; Director IST; and Miscellaneous.
Transportation maps; Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Transportation -- Washington Metropolitan Area; Local transit; Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact; Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; Stolzenbach, C. Darwin; Institute for the Study of Transportation; National Capital Transportation Agency (U.S.)
- Administrator, NCTA [National Capital Transportation Agency], 1945-1972; MS2028 Series 1; 20 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series covers Darwin Stolzenbach's term as NCTA Administrator. However, many documents pre- and post-date this time period. Those that were created prior to 1961 were most likely acquired by Stolzenbach during his tenure, to serve as background reference. Those that date from 1966 onward are apparently from collections acquired by Stolzenbach. That material which is considered consistent with documents dating from 1961-1965, such as correspondence and court decisions, are maintained in this series. Other material that, as a group, extends beyond Stolzenbach's tenure is located in the Director, IST series.
  Correspondence in the series is arranged chronologically by year, dates from 1961 to 1966 and contains Stolzenbach's own and others' letters related to the subway, highways, and general transportation, as well as NCTA administration. The Court Decisions series, arranged alphabetically by title and dating from 1876 to 1972, consists of excerpts from law review journals on various recent and historical court decisions.
  The legislation material, pre-1966, is arranged alphabetically and consists of bound and loose Congressional Record extracts, reports and summaries, testimony, and other Government Printing Office documents chronicling Federal, State, and District involvement in the development of Metro and Interstate Highways. Maps are arranged by title. These are mostly technical in layouts, but include topographical maps with proposed subway routes drawn on them.
  Material related to meetings, agendas and minutes are arranged chronologically and contains documents from meetings of the NCTA and other organizations.
  There are also miscellaneous materials that are arranged alphabetically by folder title and consist of a variety of items including contract information. Additionally, press releases are arranged chronologically and consist of draft, original, and copy news releases from the NCTA, private, and Federal organizations.
  The material related to public hearings are arranged alphabetically and are made up of hearings on the proposed I-266 route and the Three Sisters Bridge. Reports, which are arranged alphabetically, are a wide variety of bound and unbound reports, printed and typewritten, for both in-house and general use. Subject matter is generally confined to research and studies of highway and mass transit proposals.
  Speeches are arranged chronologically and consist of original and copy typescript sheets or summary notes of public and private speeches by civil and Government officials on various transportation-related topics, including testimony before Congressional committees.
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: November Report Memoranda, 1962 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Darwin Stolzenbach, 1963 January-May (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Darwin Stolzenbach, 1963 June-August (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Darwin Stolzenbach, 1963 September-December (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Committee of 100, 1966 September (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Committee of 100, 1966 October (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Committee of 100, 1966 November (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Committee of 100, 1966 December (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: handwritten notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: handwritten notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: handwritten notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: handwritten notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: handwritten notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Court Decisions: ATAA vs. Hernandez, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Court Decisions: Abbott Laboratories vs. Gardner, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Court Decisions: "Administrative Law", undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Court Decisions: Ahoyian vs. Mass. Turnpike Authority, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Court Decisions: Bank of Dearborn vs. Saxon, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Court Decisions: Bank of Haw River vs. Saxon, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Court Decisions: Booth vs. General Dynamics Corp., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Court Decisions: Braude vs. Wirtz, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Court Decisions: Brooks vs. Volpe, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Court Decisions: Capitol Vending Co. vs. Baker, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Court Decisions: Christmas vs. Warfield, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Court Decisions: "Citizen Suits under the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1970", undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Court Decisions: Citizens Association of Georgetown vs. Simonson, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Court Decisions: Citizens Committee vs. FCC, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Court Decisions: "Class Actions", undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Court Decisions: "Code of Law for D.C.,", 1900 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Court Decisions: Courtaulds vs. Dixon, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Court Decisions: Crampton vs. Zabriskie, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Court Decisions: Cudahy Parking Co. vs. Holland, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Court Decisions: B.F. Cummins Co. vs. Burleson, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Court Decisions: D.C. Federation vs. Volpe, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Court Decisions: Delta Airlines vs. CAB, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Court Decisions: Dutchess County Aviation, Inc. vs. FAA, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Court Decisions: EDF vs. Corps of Engineers, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Court Decisions: Ely vs. Velde, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Court Decisions: Embassy Dairy vs. Camalier, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Court Decisions: "Eminent Domains", undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Court Decisions: Eminente vs. Johnson, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Court Decisions: "Employment Practices,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Court Decisions: Fairmount Foods vs. Hardin, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Court Decisions: Farina Brothers vs. Commonwealth, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Court Decisions: Fastener Corp. vs. Spotnails, Inc., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Court Decisions: Fay vs. McFarland, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Court Decisions: Fuller vs. Volk, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Court Decisions: Garvey vs. Freeman, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Court Decisions: Gerstenfield vs. Jett, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Court Decisions: Glass vs. Mackie, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Court Decisions: Goddard vs. U.S., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Court Decisions: Hadnott vs. Ames, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Court Decisions: Hall vs. Cole, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Court Decisions: Hardin vs. Kentucky Utilities Co., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Court Decisions: Hazard vs. Blessing, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Court Decisions: Hobson vs. Hanson, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Court Decisions: Holm & Co. vs. Hardin, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Court Decisions: Homcy vs. Resor, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Court Decisions: "Honorable Joe Evins, Extension of Remarks", undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Court Decisions: Hornsby vs. Dobard, undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Court Decisions: Investment Co. Inst. vs. Camp, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Court Decisions: Iowa State Highway Comm. vs. Hipp, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Court Decisions: Kansas City Power & Light vs. McKay, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Court Decisions: Karahaleos vs. Secretary of HEW, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Court Decisions: Lassen vs. Arizona, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Court Decisions: Lathan vs. Volpe, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Court Decisions: Lee County School District One vs. Gardner, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Court Decisions: L'Enfant Plaza North vs. D.C. Redevelopment Land Agency, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Court Decisions: Massachusetts vs. Mellon, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Court Decisions: Mass. Avenue Heights Citizens Assoc. vs. Embassy Corp., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Court Decisions: McKaig vs. Cumberland, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Court Decisions: Monroe Co. Conservation Council vs. Volpe, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Court Decisions: Morningside-Lenox Park Assoc. vs. Volpe, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Court Decisions: Named Individuals, etc vs. Texas Highway Dept., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Court Decisions: Nolop vs. Volpe, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Court Decisions: North City Area Wide Council, Inc. vs. Romney, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Court Decisions: Norwalk Core vs. Norwalk Redevelopment Agency, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Court Decisions: Pacific Power and Light vs. Federal Power Commission, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Court Decisions: Paepike vs. Building Commission, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Court Decisions: Pangburn vs. Civic Aeron Board, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Court Decisions: Poole Broadcasting Co. vs. FCC, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Court Decisions: Protestants & Other Americans, etc vs. Watson, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Court Decisions: "Public Health and Welfare", undated (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Court Decisions: Quinn vs. Dougherty, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Court Decisions: Reichelderfer vs. Quinn, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Court Decisions: Reiter vs. Holtxoff, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Court Decisions: Road Review League vs. Boyd, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Court Decisions: Roberts vs. Bradfiend, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Court Decisions: Robbins vs. Department of Public Works, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Court Decisions: Ruckelshaus vs. Izaak Walton League, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Court Decisions: Rudolph vs. Hunt, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Court Decisions: Rudolph vs. Warwick, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Court Decisions: S&L Associates vs. Washington Township, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Court Decisions: Sensytrol Corp. vs. RCA, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Court Decisions: Shannon vs. US Dept. of HUD, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Court Decisions: Sierra Club vs. Morton, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Court Decisions: Singer Sewing Machine Co. vs. NLRB, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Court Decisions: Smith vs. Government of Virgin Islands, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Court Decisions: Smith vs. Sol D. Adler Realty, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Court Decisions: Smyth vs. Kaufman, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Court Decisions: South Hill Neighborhood Assoc. vs. Romney, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Court Decisions: Stratton vs. City of Riverton, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Court Decisions: "Subpoena Deuces Tecum", undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Court Decisions: Thompson vs. Fugate, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Court Decisions: Triangle Improvement Council vs. Ratlike, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Court Decisions: Udall vs. Federal Power Comm., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Court Decisions: Union Savings Bank of Patchogue vs. Saxon, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Court Decisions: United Church of Christ vs. FCC, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Court Decisions: "US Constitution, 5th Amendment,", 1966 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Court Decisions: United States Law Weekly, 39:33 and other days, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Court Decisions: U.S. vs. Acres of Land, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Court Decisions: VJPA vs. Federal Power Comm., 1958 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Court Decisions: Virgo Corp. vs. Paiewonsky, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Court Decisions: Walter vs. McFarland, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Court Decisions: Weaver vs. Ives, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Court Decisions: Wellford vs. Ruckelshaus, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Court Decisions: Wisconsin vs. Federal Power Comm., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Court Decisions: Wirtz vs. Local 20, IUOE, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 35)